hi my name is Paul from physics hype
today I want to give you a very quick
overview of the concept of lenses law
please like share and subscribe and
maybe buy me a coffee the link is in the
description below if you want a more
fulsome discussion of lenses law please
check out the link there or the link in
the description below where I give a
more detailed analysis today is just a
short version of it what is lenses law
well lenses law is related to the
concept of Faraday's law and let's write
the Faraday's law down which basically
says that if you generate an EMF because
so we have a change of flux with respect
to time that a metal is experiencing
then there's a negative sign that refers
to the concept of lenses law and lenses
law says that whatever the EMF that is
generated will always produce a polarity
that opposes the one that generates it
and so one way we can describe this is
using a coil so let's say I have a coil
like this
and I'm going to connect this to a
voltmeter and I've insert a North Pole
and I push that into the coil we have a
magnetic field around my bar magnet and
it's going to enter the coil which
results in an EMF Genie being generated
and as a result in this case a current
is produced now the card that is
produced will always produce a magnetic
field that opposes it so as I push this
in I am going to produce a North Pole in
this end it's going to not want to go in
it's going to experience a force of
repulsion now because of the fact that
there's a North Pole over here that
means I will generate a South bolt over
here and So based on my diagram my code
is going to go from there to there so if
I pull that magnet out the north is now
moving away that will produce a polarity
here that is South to oppose it it's
moving away it will create a force that
wants to pull it back in which will
therefore oppose the change that causes
it and so therefore the kind therefore
that is in used is determined by what is
happening over here and it'll always
oppose and as a result that is going to
be consistent with the conservation of
energy because as you pull it in you
require energy to push it down and so
that requires energy to be produced over
here so that is lenses law please like
share and subscribe put a comment down
below and consider supporting me by
buying me a coffee take care bye for now